Ladies and gentlemen, a very warm
welcome to ICIC Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited Q1 FY24
earnings conference call from the senior
management we have with us today Mr.
Bharot Daz Gupta MD and CEO of the
company Mr. Gopal Balachandran CFO and
CRO Mr. Sanjiv Mantri executive director
and Mr. Alo Agarwal, Executive Director.
Please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involved risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to defer materially from the current
views being expressed.
As a reminder, all participant lines
will be in listenonly mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Bharas Gupta, MD and CEO ICIC Lombard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir. Thank you and good
evening to each one of you. Uh thank you
for joining the earnings conference call
of IC Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited for Q1 FI 2024. I will give you
a brief overview of the industry trends
and developments that we have witnessed
in the past few months. Post this our
CFO Mr. Gopal Balachendran will share
the financial performance of the company
for the quarter ended June 30, 2023.
India's real GDP uh growth recorded a
strong stronger growth than estimates
and has surpassed the prepandemic
levels. Domestic demand conditions
remain supportive of growth on the back
of improving household consumption and
investment activity.
Urban demand remains resilient with
indicators such as passenger vehicle
sales and domestic passenger traffic
posted go growth on a year-on-year
basis. This growth can have some impact
from headwinds such as weak external
demand, volatating global financial
conditions and prolonged geopolitical
tensions
for the quarter. As per data published
by CM, the new vehicle sales continued
to grow year on year for private car and
two wheelers. However, the growth
narrowed in the month of June uh this
year. The growth in sales of commercial
vehicle was at a double digit during the
quarter. Two wheeler sales for the
quarter in terms of volumes remained
below the prep pandemic levels. Health
insurance continued to remain the
largest contributor to overall growth.
The commercial lines witnessed growth in
in line with the current market
environment.
While the fire market has seen some rate
pressures, the inherent growth remains
intact.
The focus of the government on
infrastructure has led to a 41.3% growth
during Q1 of FYI 2024 in the engineing
line of business and it's expected to
show encouraging growth in the future as
well. We remain optimistic that the
industry will continue to grow given f
favorable macros, regulatory changes,
low penetration and positive consumer
sentiment.
Speaking of the performance, the general
insurance industry delivered a GDPI
growth of 17.9% for Q1 of this year.
Overall, the underwriting performance
improved with a combined ratio of the
industry at 115.8 for FI 2023 as against
109.1 for FI 2022. For motor business,
the combined ratio for the industry
remained elevated at 121.1 for FI 2023,
up from 115.6 for FI 2022. The combined
ratio for motor and H1 of FI20 2023 was
123.5 which improved to 118.8 for H2 of
FI23.
Moving to regulatory updates, the
authority on June 30th 2023 published
guidelines for remuneration of
non-executive directors and key
management personnel prescribing limits
on remination age and tenure.
Moving to business impact for us in Q1
2024 the company grew by 18.9% as
compared to the industry growth of
17.9%.
Excluding crop the company grew by 19.2%
as against the industry growth of 17.4%.
Coming to the growth of key segments
during the quarter in property and
casualty line of business we grew at
17.0%
which is which is higher than the
industry growth of 7.8%.
Further during the quarter we accreted
market share across all segments such as
fire, marine engineering and liability.
Discont discontinuation of the IIB rates
had a moderate impact which is in line
with our expectations. However, we will
continue to monitor the development in
coming quarters.
In motor the growth was defined at 5.3%
for the quarter while we grew at 10.8%
8% in June. While we witnessed further
we witnessed month-on-month growth in uh
new private car segment during the
quarter with no motor TV price hike we
have rebalanced our portfolio resulting
in a commercial vehicle mix at 21% and
two wheeler mix at 30.3% for Q1 of 24.
The health segment continued to be the
fastest growing segment for the
industry. During the quarter we grew at
40.4%
which is higher than the industry growth
of 20.7%.
In group health employer employee
segment, the change in underlying
industry pricing sentiment resulted in
customers moving towards customers
towards companies with better
underwriting and service capabilities
resulting in our group health segment to
grow by 43.9% during the quarter.
As a result of our continued investment
in retail health distribution, we have
outgrown the industry growth of 18% in
Q1 24 with a growth of 22.8%.
This was driven by business source
through retail health agency vertical
growth of 25.6%.
I would also like to share that our
one-stop uh uh solution for all
insurance and wellness needle take care
app has surpassed 5.6 million user
downloads till date. The incremental
download for the quarter was close to 1
million. For Q1 of this year the premium
source through Altakeare contributed 58
588.0 0 million to the GDPI reflecting a
five times year-on-year increase.
Our bank insurance and key relationship
group uh grew at 27.3 3% this quarter.
Post pandemic steady credit growth along
with deep mining and increase in wallet
share and distribution partners has been
the key growth driver.
Our business source through our digital
one team grew by 24.7%.
Overall, our digital focus has enabled
us to increase our digital revenues,
including I'll take care app revenues to
3.12 billion rupees, which accounts for
accounts for 4.9% of our overall GDP for
the quarter.
We continue to make significant
investments in modernizing our
technology architecture. After moving to
the cloud in uh FI 2022, we modernized a
number of our front-end applications.
Being on the cloud and transitioning to
to cloud native has led to increase in
reliability of our technology platforms
as evidenced by the reduction in error
tickets by error tickets by close to 71%
this year. In the last year at the same
time we have seen an 86% reduction in
response times across some of our
digital channel partners.
Our uh you know responsible intelligent
assistant we call RIA our chatbot has
enabled our DIY adoption by 3.4 four
times over a 13-month period. Alongside
transitioning to the cloud and
modernization, we completed the
migration of applications and data from
the US Bharti AXA data center to our
application platforms and cloud data
center in just 14 months. We believe
that this was one of the fastest
migrations of this scale in the
insurance industry globally.
We also continue to remain focused on
leveraging our digital capabilities and
building claims efficiency. Case in
point towards motor claim settlement
process. We introduced cloud calling
feature enabling over two lakh customers
during the quarter to connect seamlessly
using a dedicated virtual number. 81% of
our customers filed e claim form in Q124
up from 67% in Q1 of last year. In Q124
through our PPN uh network the preferred
payment garage network we were able to
service 60% of our nonoem claims up from
40% in Q123. Resundantly our overall NPS
for non-cashless claims improved to 62%
uh for the year till May 2023 up from
42% for Q1 of 23. Also, NPS for cashless
claims increased improved to 68% for YTD
May 23, up from 60% in Q1 of last year.
To conclude, I would like to summarize
that we are well positioned for the
future. We remain focused on growth
levers such as innovation, digital
advancements, launching new products,
strengthening our distribution engine,
rationalizing cost while scaling up our
preferred lines of business. I will now
request Gopal to take you through the
financial numbers for the recently
concluded quarter. Thanks, Barup. And uh
good evening to each one of you. I will
now give you a brief overview of the
financial performance of the company for
Q1 FI24. We have uploaded the results
presentation on our website. You can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers. Gross direct
premium income of the company was at
63.87 billion rupees in Q1 FI24 as
against 53.70 billion rupees in Q1 FI23.
A growth of 18.9% against the industry
growth of 17.9%.
Excluding crop, GDPI growth as a company
was at 19.2% which was higher than the
industry growth of 17.4% in Q1 FI24. Our
GDPI growth was primarily driven by
growth in the preferred segments. The
overall GDPI growth of our property and
casualty segment grew by 17% at rupes
22.86 billion in Q1 FI24 as against
rupees 19.54 billion in Q1 FI23. On the
retail side of the business, GDP of the
motor segment was at rupes 18.75 billion
in Q1 FI24 as against rupes 17.82
billion in Q1 FI23 registering a growth
of 5.3%.
Our agents including the point of sale
distribution count was at 1 lak 17,149
as on June 30, 2023 up from around 1
lakh 13,000 as on March 31, 2023. The
advanced premium was rupes 32.63 63
billion as at June 30, 2023 as against
rupes 32.17 billion as at March 31,
2023. Resultantly combined ratio was
103.8% for Q1 FI24 as against 104.1%
for Q1 FI23 excluding the impact of
cyclone loss cyclone losses of.35
billion rupees. The combined ratio was
102.9% for Q1 FI24.
The technical reserves which are
presented as a part of the reserving
disclosures are not discounted as per
the current regulatory framework.
However, globally we understand
technical reserves technical reserves
are presented on a discounted basis. If
we were to discount the technical
reserves particularly for the longtail
businesses such as motor third party
which constitutes around 80% of our
total outstanding and IBNR reserves. Our
current reported combined ratio of
104.5%
for FY 2023 would look better by around
400 basis points. Our investment assets
rose to rupes 449.05 billion as at June
30, 2023 from rupees 431.8 billion as at
March 31, 2023. Our investment leverage
net of borrowings was 4.16 times as at
June 30, 2023 as against 4.15 times as
at March 31, 2023. Investment income was
at rupees 8.23 billion in Q1 FI24 as
against rupees 6.55 billion in Q1 FI23.
Our capital gains stood at rupees 1.23
billion in Q1 FI24 as against rupees 32
billion in Q1 FI23.
Our profit before tax grew by 11.8% at
rupees 5.2 billion in Q1 FI24 as against
rupees 4.65 billion in Q1 FI23.
Consequently, profit after tax grew by
11.8 8% at rupes 3.90 billion Q1 FI24 as
against rupes 3.49 49 billion in Q1
FI23.
Return on average equity was 14.7% in Q1
FI24 as against 15% in Q1 FI23. Solveny
ratio was at 2.53 times as at June 30,
2023 as against 2.51 times as at March
31, 2023 continued to be higher than the
minimum regulatory requirement of 1.5
times. As I conclude, I would like to
reiterate we continue to stay focused on
driving profitable growth, sustainable
value creation and safeguarding interest
of policy holders at all times. I would
like to thank you for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take any questions that you may have.
Thank you.
Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session.
Anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on their touchstone
telephone.
If you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question queue, you may press star
and two. Participants are requested to
use handsets while asking a question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question QSM is.
We have our first question from the line
of P Jen from Losal. Please go ahead. Uh
yeah hi good evening everyone. Uh this
is a few few questions. Uh firstly could
you talk us through the loss ratios you
know like u so x catastrophic what would
be the loss ratios and where is this
loss ratio kind of sitting so you know
if I look at a group health loss ratio
your total health loss ratio is at
78.7%.
Could you split that up for us for you
know in terms of core retail retail
health and group health and where is
this catastrophic loss exactly sitting
in which line item which of the segments
pre uh uh in so far as the breakup of
the overall health loss ratio numbers
that you see which is 78.7% for Q and
FI24 the breakup of that for employer
employee or the group health is at about
92.6%.
the retail indemnity business is at
about 64.2%. So that's a breakup for the
overall health. And to your other
question in terms of where is the impact
of cyclone losses largely sitting upon
it is predominantly in the property and
the casualty line of businesses which is
in the fire and engineering line of
businesses. Predominantly a very small
proportion of claims is there in motor
but predominantly a large part of the
impact on the cyclone is in fire and
engineering. The combined impact as what
we gave at the part of the opening
remarks for this quarter the net impact
of claims on account of cyclone losses
has been about 35 crores. Okay. Uh any
reason for this for a very high loss
ratio on the group side is there a spike
in terms of number of claims uh or
frequency or severity.
So no specific uh in general if you see
what we have been speaking about pre
even in the past on the employer
employee segment generally we have
spoken about the loss ratios to stay in
the range of around that 95% kind of
threshold between 90 to 95 because it
primarily compris comprises of two books
as what we have spoken one is relatively
large corporates which kind of runs at a
loss ratio anywhere ranging between 95
to 100 and then we have the relativelyme
which is a small and the mid corporate
portfolio which runs at a loss ratio
experience between 90 to 95. So on
balance historically we have run the
book at a loss ratio as I said around
that 95% threshold. Currently for the
quarter as I said the number stands at
about 92.6. So hence to that extent no
specific uh changes when we see in the
context of whether let's say an increase
in frequency or increase in severity
with respect to claims. actually price
if you look at our last year full year
group health loss ratio uh that was
roughly about 95. So if you look at the
current quarter is actually lower uh we
don't see any uh any significant
pressure on the health loss ratio side
retail is still performing well and
group health because the cost of
acquisition is low uh this is typically
where the loss ratio uh lands.
Got that. And coming to motor segment uh
you know from again from a uh
profitability perspective and uh the mix
that you have change of mix that you
spoken about to you know going away from
commercial vehicles would that be a
strategy for FI204
or from a longerterm perspective and
secondly could you talk about you know
like for many quarters we've spoken
about some green shoots on the OD
pricing uh but you know that's that's
not really reflecting very heavily in
terms of numbers. While you mentioned
about the industry loss ratios kind of
combined ratios kind of uh improving
between first half and second half is
there any more uh bigger trends that you
know you see further improvement or it's
just you know kind of uh getting
arrested at the current levels
so on the first one commercial vehicles
uh I think some of the uh granular calls
that we took certain strategic calls
that we took over the last two to three
years which we've talked about I think
we are kind of staying invested with
this with that uh the bit of
rationalization that we did was because
the TP price hike this year didn't
happen. So with our estimate of
inflation as we've already always talked
about then certain marginal portfolios
being becoming become unviable. Having
said that if you see our 21% is still
higher than what our traditional CV
market had been which was about 15 16%.
And our sense is that uh we are not
planning to reduce it significantly.
It'll probably be in the similar
ballpark uh you know 20 plus minus. Uh
coming to your um uh coming to your
question on OD again if you look at uh
this quarter loss ratio for us in the OD
compared to last year uh you see a
improvement. Yeah, having said that the
expectation that we've had is some of
the aggression on sourcing side given
the expensive management will cap the
flexibility to some of the players. We
would we were expecting some more
rationalization, some more improvement.
At this point in time, we've not seen it
but I think we kind of reached a level
where we've uh ironed out most of the
marginal portfolios. Uh so most of the
pain is behind us as we think. Okay. Go
back. Last question. Mr. Jen, I request
you to join back the queue sir.
Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, in
order to ensure that the management is
able to answer queries from all
participants, please restrict your
questions to two at a time. You may join
back the queue for follow-up questions.
We'll take our next question from the
line of Sankit Kota from Aendis Park.
Please go ahead. Yeah. Uh thank you for
the opportunity. Uh uh my question is
around the motor business. If I if I
look at the numbers uh consistently it
has been improving from second quarter
or first quarter of FI23
that number is around 67. So just wanted
to understand that that this number of
67 is sustainable or or or or actually
want to understand more in detail what
what corrective measures you have taken
so that so that except for except for
the choice of not seizing the market
share uh which has led to the
improvement in the into improvement in
the loss ratio in the motor segment OD
segment rather uh that's one one thing
and and second just wanted to again
understand is this this techare app
which you said today today probably
contributes almost 1%age of your GDP I
uh uh in in in the quarter one you have
done. So so mean want want to understand
how how you see this channel to be a
cross-ell upsell channel uh which
products and how much it can potentially
contribute to the entire entire GWP as
time progress.
So Ske on the first question uh you know
on motor OD side there multiple things
that we've been doing and you know in a
sense we've been saying that a lot of
you know heavy lifting we did last year
uh one is the selection uh the marginal
portfolios we've let go uh that has an
impact uh so our sourcing or which is
the target loss ratio when we source a
business that has also come out. The
second is on the claim side. There's
been a huge amount of effort that we
have done more in terms of uh some of
the abuse that was that uh that uh
generally happens but we believe had
picked up postco. Um so on the claims
control we've done a lot of work on
using data analytics uh to uh uh reduce
waste and abuse. Uh thirdly we talked
about the percentage increase in PPL
that also gives us some savings on the
claim side. So there are multiple
initiatives that has happened and you
know it is sustainable again we'll have
to wait to see market conduct but we are
reasonably hopeful that we should be
able to sustain this at this current
level. uh coming to your point on take
care the numbers that we gave out uh
it's about five times of last year's
similar number for the quarter but uh in
aggregate for the company even if we add
this I'll take care number to the
overall digital business it's as we said
it's about 4.9% of our uh of our total
business let's say I take care
contribution for this quarter was about
58 crores 588 million so it's not a
material number as yet but we believe
this is actually helping us at multiple
levels one is uh customer engagement
retention. We see some loss, you know,
better loss ratio for clients which use
I'll take care in group levels. We see a
better retention of uh you know
profitable accounts in the corporate
side and we are looking at how we can
use that further in terms of
strategically in terms of increasing uh
cross-ell and upsell. uh that's work in
progress but still honestly in terms of
aggregate numbers uh we are very
heartened by the scale the speed at
which it's picking up but uh still small
in the overall scheme of things
uh just one one one clarification is
this tech car you are able to manage
cost of predominantly retail health at
58 crores or 59 crores or or or it is it
is other products also you are seeing
attraction it's other bits of product we
are seeing two wheelers we are seeing uh
health we are seeing uh you know uh more
you know private car we are seeing uh
employees of uh you know corporates
buying policies uh on their own so it's
a mix of uh most products that we have
there. Got it. Got it. And finally last
one goal if you can explain the uh the
the the reason why the commission cost
has boosted. Overall expense has not
changed but but the commission cost has
gone up but but expense has come down.
So, so you have seen that EOM impact
already visible with respect to shift
from advertisement cost to the
commission.
So, I think SKT uh if you recollect I
think the way we have always talked
about is I think to look at the
businesses from an overall combined
perspective because as we keep saying
there are different models of sourcing
that exist in the market. I mean there
are segments which relatively run on ILR
and low extensive management and and the
other way around. So which is what now
when you look at let's say even from a
quarter one perspective I think I would
kind of always keep urging to look at it
more from an expense of management
standpoint rather than looking at uh any
breakups uh around that. So if you look
at the overall expense of management in
terms of the breakup of the combined
ratio that we reported of about 103.8%
for quarter 1 of which the loss ratio
was about 74.1% and the balance which is
almost about 29.7%
is the uh expensive management number.
This if you look at it for quarter 1 of
last year the expense of management
number was about 32.1%.
And uh again when you look at it even
with the quarter four quarter 4 the
expense of management number was about
29.9%. So even on a sequential basis I
think we have seen an improvement in the
overall expense of management and even
on a year-on-year basis I think clearly
there have been an improvement in the
overall expense of management. That's
the way we would want you to look at
because as I said there are different
models of sourcing that exists and and
and as a company that's what we would
want to kind of look at. Got it.
Perfect. That's it for myself. Thanks.
Thank you. We have a next question from
the line of Nidesh Jen from Investic.
Please go ahead. Uh thanks for the
opportunity. So firstly uh if you break
the digital business, what percentage of
business is coming from our own website?
uh plus I'll take care and how are the
trends in that segment on a Y basis.
So if you look at the way we uh manage
this business, there is uh the digital
one team which looks at if you remember
we had said there are two uh objectives
that we they have one is uh the website
business growth and the other is working
with the digital ecosystem partners uh
you know and and and we look at it
together that that growth for this
quarter is about 37.8%.
uh the IT care number as you said is
relatively small but that's grown from a
small base at five times uh you know
it's over 500 you know it's 400%
if you look at the annual disclosure I
think last year uh in the public
disclosure the data indicates that uh
the growth from our own website has not
been that uh strong it has been
flattening out uh growth is largely
coming from the digital ecosystem so are
those trends continuing in this quarter
also or uh and because uh the business
coming from our own website will be much
more uh much more better quality low
much more uh profitable probably over a
period of time. So how we think about
the strategy on the digital side from
sourcing business from our own website
sorry uh so it's a combination of both
uh uh so obviously we look at all of
them are preferred channels of sourcing
whether you look at business through
website business through alliances and
even let's say the taker opportunity as
what bar explained for us all the three
segments have grown uh whether you look
at it from a website standpoint whether
you look at it even from an alliance
standpoint
In fact during the quarter we have
further strengthened the number of
alliances tieups that we have and that's
the reason why that part that that part
of the business has done uh phenomenally
quite well and overall as we said the
digital one contribution in terms of
revenue for the company for this quarter
has grown at about 24.7%.
Sure. Secondly, uh last year we put out
a strategy that we will focus on higher
loss ratio and low opex ratio business
in the motor OD segment. Uh so how while
if you look at our loss ratios have
improved uh quite a bit. Uh and opex
ratio has also seen some improvement. Uh
so how how is the uh how is the trend
there where the uh how the share of that
business shaping up uh on overall motor
GDP?
So again again uh again it's a
combination of both Nidesh is what I
would say I think what we put out as a
part of our opening remarks I think for
us if you look at this particular
quarter I think the growth on new
private car has kind of come back uh
which is kind of exhibited when you look
at it sequentially on a month basis I
think the growth uh in new private car
seems to be kind of doing well having
said and that typically also comes with
a relatively better uh loss experience
having said that I think we are also
kind of increasingly focusing on exactly
the point that you mentioned with
respect to focusing on relatively older
vehicle segments which also comes with a
relatively high LR and let's say lower
cost of acquisition and that's again
reflecting also in the expense of
management number and if you recolct
what we have been talking about
historically our proportion of motor
business coming in through the OEM
channel of contribution used to be in
the range of 75 to 80%. increasingly
that proportion of contribution of
business of motors coming in from let's
say the OEM channel of distribution is
will be in the range of about 60 65%. So
directionally I think what we have been
trying to do is to balance the overall
portfolio between contribution from OEM
dealership agency as well as the earlier
point that we made in terms of the
digital opportunity that one sees.
Sure. Sure. Uh that's it from my side.
Thank you.
Thank you. We have our next question
from the line of Shrea Shivani from
CLSA. Please go ahead. Yeah. Hi. Thank
you. Uh I have two questions. First is
on the motor segment uh total motor
segment. So uh if I compare uh Lombard's
uh both loss ratio and growth across uh
the private peers, I would uh
specifically look at the private general
insurers. uh so many of them would have
just a few percentage point higher loss
ratio on the segment uh but they're e
they're delivering about you know 15%
growth uh in this quarter uh as per the
ADA data. So what can we what can we
expect for Lombard uh Lombard's motor
segment for the full year and any
guidance on the over overall premium
growth for FI24? FI24 that's the first
question and uh the second question is
uh on the crop loss ratio it seems a
little higher uh at more than 100% and
last year I remember you guys had shared
that um the crop program that you had
participated in was a 80 120 capped plan
something like that so so if you can
help us understand that as well
so the second part is I'll kind of
answer uh answer that sha so in general
if you recolct
uh obviously the claim development cycle
takes time and that's the reason uh from
a conservical standpoint whenever we
book the revenues given that we don't
have complete experience of loss
development we end up providing it to a
100% uh loss ratio basis. uh so which is
why when you look at that numbers uh you
will find the loss ratios to be a bit
elevated but when you when the actual
experience starts to kind of play out
you will obviously start getting that uh
reflected on actuals. So hence we will
and typically it roughly takes about two
quarters for the loss development to
play out in the crop segment. So as and
when we get to see the impact of the
cycle uh we will kind of actualize uh
those numbers. uh to to your first point
on what is it that we can expect on
overall growth for the company as a
whole. I think in line with what we have
spoken uh as we always keep saying the
market needs to get better in terms of
uh pricing uh at this point of time if
you would have seen for quarter 1 I
think we have had almost close to almost
about 200 basis points out performance
relative to the market growth numbers
when you look at X of crop uh and so
that's clearly the expectation that we
have as a company we have we have the
necessary strength in so far as
distribution claim service and
technology is concerned And hence to
that extent from an overall market
standpoint we would obviously want to
expect us continuing to have similar
kind of uh outperformance. Now within
that to your first point on how does one
see on motor as I said again when you
look at it on a sequential basis month
on month I think clearly we have been
able to possibly arrest the extent of uh
degrowth that we had seen in that
particular segment. So for example in
April we had a degrowth in a motor for
the month of May we had a positive
growth of about 5% and for the month of
June we had a growth of almost about
10%. So sequentially I think we have
been able to kind of get better and the
extent of gap between the industry
growth numbers and let's say the growth
that we have been exhibiting is kind of
getting narrowed down. So there again I
think and so and so the only thing that
would watch out for to your point on
what we could expect for the rest of the
year is the the adherance to the expense
of management guidelines uh that's
coming to post from this year. In fact I
was just when we were looking at the
FI23 numbers that's now out for the
entire market as a whole almost close to
2/3 of the industry participants have
their expense of management number
greater than the regulatory prescribed
limit of 30% or 35%. uh so this clearly
calls for an action which is what I
presume even the regulator would be
significantly uh putting a focus on once
all companies start putting out their Q1
numbers I'm sure they will start looking
at the expense of management numbers for
the overall market as a whole and within
that each individual companies in terms
of how they have exhibited and uh once
some of these things starts to correct
uh over the period of time obviously as
I said in so far as our positioning is
concerned I think we should be able to
kind of uh see relatively better growth
uh even in motor as a category and it
comment that you had in terms of the
loss ratios uh uh you know I think as
we've been explaining this for for some
time that when you look at motor uh if
you split the loss ratio between one
damage and and third party you'll see
certain patterns I mean you know you can
do the analysis yourself and in third
party uh again if you do a bit deeper
dive on the reserving picture which is
now available to all of you. You'll be
able to figure out uh the reserving
practices uh and that will probably
throw some light on the loss ratio
numbers of some of the players in the
market. Got it. Got it. So, so one uh
one just uh clarification I wanted uh
the retail indemnity loss ratio that you
mentioned at 64.2
uh this is 64.2 for the retail indemnity
sold by agents or the ones which is the
one which is getting sold by ICIC bank.
No, not the group group structure. The
recent retail indemnity is the uh
individual retail indemity. And what is
the loss ratio of the ICIC bank uh
portion that is getting sold by IC bank?
Level of detail that's not fair on the
distributor also. Sure. Sure. Okay.
Thank you. Thank you. We have a next
question from the line of Rishi
Junjunwala from IFL Institutional
Equities. Please go ahead.
Yeah, thanks for the opportunity. Just a
couple of questions uh firstly on the
health side. So um can you tell us um
you know in the you know retail health
the 23% yearon-year growth that we have
seen how much of that is driven by
pricing increase that you had taken in
February and secondly on the corporate
side there is a significant growth that
has come here um you know is that being
driven by um you know the the normal
group health plans or there is a large
component of um you know the credit
protect plans also which are coming here
and and is that the reason why unexpired
risk reserve has shot up quite
significantly for us in this quarter.
So on the second part Trishi uh to your
point on the uh one on the I'll just
kind of talk about the commercial lines
as a category and within that then I
will talk about your corporate health or
let's say the uh group health uh point
that you wanted to understand across
commercial lines I think we have
actually been able to exhibit
significant market share as what we kind
of also put out as a part of the opening
remarks in fact relative to an industry
growth of which is singledigit 7.8% 8%
our growth has been about 17%. And this
spans across fire, marine, engineering,
liability etc etc across the key
commercial lines and there the growth is
aided by uh across all factors which is
it is driven by volume increase it is
equally driven by I would say uh
accretion of market share and
specifically now also in the context of
corporate health we have also been able
to see accretion in pricing as well. uh
so it's been an all round kind of growth
that one has seen in the overall
commercial lines portfolio. To your
second point on now within the group
health or let's say within the corporate
health again it's been a combination of
both. Uh we have uh as you would kind of
recollect uh some of the participants in
the market had exhibited significant
underwriting losses particularly in the
corporate health space and there have
been clear instructions that they have
given to their respective operating
offices to get better on underwriting.
That's exactly is what we kind of wait
for as opportunities for us to kind of
write businesses because as I said we
have the necessary backend uh strength
in terms of distribution and uh let's
say claim service to our advantage. So
hence we have been able to again accrete
market share uh from some of those
companies into us where customer starts
to look at more in terms of service uh
as the basis of placing uh the risk. uh
so and the growth is aided by accretion
in market share again volume we do see
in some sectors incremental hiring being
done by some of the corporates concerned
and to that extent it is also
volumedriven and three it's also a
function of as I said uh the relative
overall growth that one has seen uh
health is also aided by I would say uh
reasonable growth even on the bank
assurance base as we had kind of put out
even as a part of the opening remarks or
bank which comprises of distribution
through banks and our key relationship
group partners. That's again done
reasonably well uh at almost about 27%
growth uh on the back of again
reasonable growth coming back in terms
of credit uh dispersements. What one
would watch for is obviously the extent
of dispersement levels as we head into
the subsequent quarters. I think that we
will wait for in terms of how the
development uh takes place.
Understood. And second question you know
while you explained about the expense of
management thing and you know that to
look at on an overall basis and that's
anyways what we are going to do but just
from a you know purpose of understanding
uh wanted to understand the change in um
commission and the business uh promotion
um is it purely a reclassification issue
from books of accounts perspective from
the way you are now paying to the
distributors or is Is there any actually
on ground business model change also?
So if you ask us as as we always keep
saying uh Rishi I think at the end of
the day we always look at the overall
cost of acquisition in terms of the way
we kind of uh do businesses and that's
the reason why I kind of specifically
put out that number in the context of
expense of management. uh and that's
what I would urge uh to kind of look at
and uh honestly the kind of split
between what constitutes commission what
constitutes let's say my overall
operating expenses all of them are baked
in as a part of our operating model
fundamentally if you ask us have we
changed anything in so far as the
underlying way of doing business
honestly not there is no specific change
that one has kind of done and hence
which is why I'm saying that one should
start looking at the numbers more from
an expensive management standpoint
rather than trying to look at splits
between how much has been the growth in
commissions and how much has been the
changes in operating expenses.
Okay, thank you all of them.
Thank you.
We have our next question from the line
of Ain Singh from MK Global. Please go
ahead.
Yeah. Hi, good evening. Uh two
questions. Uh so first one is more on uh
commercial lines. Uh your particular
fire engineering. So there were was sort
of a multiple factors affecting the
pricing and all. So just I mean if you
can give some color on that adjusting
for your cyclone losses if there has
been sort of a impact on overall claims
ratio because of the pricing environment
or if you can quantify also the price
changes effectively that happened in
this quarter. So that's on commercial
line. Second on group health or employer
employee part if you can provide some
sort of uh you know either quantify or
some uh qualitative uh disclosure in
terms of how has been your experience on
the uh you know uh business that you
have initially acquired precovid period
and continue to renew I mean with price
hikes and the business you have acquired
say last year so are there sort of a
difference in terms of the claims
experience in uh these two sets. These
are two questions. Thank you. So u let
me take the second one and Gopal can
give you the split of uh let's say the
commercial lines business in aggregate
commercial line business there's been
some uh softening on the fire side for
the reasons that we've been talking
about which is that the IB rate is no
longer there but it's a it's well in
line with our estimates. Uh so it's a
singledigit change uh not a material
reduction that we have seen in the first
quarter but we'll have to be watchful of
how this progresses uh for the rest of
the year but till now it's largely been
uh you know in line with expectations
the difference in the uh you know the
loss ratios for fire and engineering
without with Gopal will answer that
separately coming back to your uh
question on group health a uh I think
The real good news for us was that you
know the uh accounts that we had precoid
um you know and we've been talking about
this in the past as well uh you know
from July of the year after the second
wave we started increasing prices by
between 15 to 20% and we used to see
almost 90% more than 90% retention of
the large accounts. So I think the
service proposition that we've delivered
uh you know the the uh various uh
features of take care etc. I think
overall we've had good experience in
terms of retaining these uh accounts. Uh
this year uh for the reasons that Gopal
explained, we are seeing a good traction
in business moving from uh some of the
other uh you know companies that's come
coming in. Uh the way we are pricing it
is again in line with our you know
general practice of being uh disciplined
about underwriting. So the question then
is that will these guys also renew next
year if prices go down that we'll have
to wait for. But the approach that we
take is even when we go in with uh any
of these accounts the approach is to
look at customers who are not uh you
know price seekers every year who switch
from one company to the other. But to
look at companies who generally been uh
stable with one insurer for some time
maybe wanting to move now because of
service experiences or because pricing
has significantly gone up and come close
to our numbers and we are able to get a
slight premium over the market prices.
So on balance I don't see a big
difference between the accounts that we
had in the past to the accounts that we
have got now on the Google. Yeah. and uh
vin to your point on uh what could be
the potential impact on some of this
pricing changes and let's say cyclone
led impact as bar said I think so far as
the price decline is a single-digit
number roughly in that range of I would
say between 5 to 7% kind of decline in
pricing is what one had seen and that's
on expected lines that's what we had
mentioned even during the April earnings
call at the time when the guidelines had
come into force uh which is the reason
why if you see for overall market Higher
growth for quarter 1 is far more tippid
at let's say at 5.9 or 6%. Uh even
despite that if you look at for IC alone
we have again had an outperformance in
that category. Uh we have grown at
almost about 10% in fire as a line of
business. So that's the impact in so far
as pricing is concerned. On the other
part what we discussed even in the April
earnings call if you recollect is also
the hardening of reinsurance rates and
therefore to that extent we also had
seen an improve increase in the XL cost.
What effectively happens is the NEP does
a catch up because typically your cost
of Excel starts reaching in quarter one
and as the book kind of grows the
earnings play through over the remaining
quarters. So now when you look at the
loss ratios what is put out in the
investor deck for fire let's say at
about 85% for quarter 1 and let's say
98.6%
for engineering. Now this has the impact
of the XL cost. It also has the impact
of I would say losses from cyclone as
what I kind of mentioned. Uh very
difficult to kind of separately call out
the impact of the XL cost. But if I were
to just exclude the uh impact of cyclone
losses, the loss ratio on fire which is
at about 85% will look like about 64
65%. And engineering which is looking
like about 98.6% will look like about uh
close to about 80 82%.
in that range. So that's the kind of
numbers that one sees in so far as
excluding the catalosses are concerned.
But as I said Q1
particularly for engineering is
relatively more longtail as the project
starts to kind of uh build over a period
of time is where you will see a
relatively larger proportion of earnings
coming through and to that extent you
will always find possibly the Q1 loss
ratios to be a bit more skewed.
Okay. Okay. Yeah. So I mean on group
health broadly I can expect that the 90%
broadly is for your old book as well as
new book. I mean there's no difference
in experience. I request you to join
back the queue sir as there are other
participants waiting.
Thank you.
We have our next question from the line
of Swarnab Mukharji from BNK securities.
Please go ahead. Yeah. Hi sir. Thank you
for the opportunity. Uh so couple of
questions. Uh first on the retail
health. So sir you mentioned around
64ish uh loss ratio in the retail Indian
portfolio. Um I just I was just
wondering that historically you have
told that you have run this uh book at
around loss ratios of between uh 65 to
70%. So is there a possibility that
we'll uh push the pedal a little bit
more in terms of growth uh going ahead
so that we are we in between that mark
because profitability wise I think we
are much better than where where we were
running the business. uh so whether we
should expect to see growth panning out
at a faster rate and uh you know much
much more higher than the industry given
that our market share is still lower
than what our company average market
share is uh across categories. So that
is the first question on retail health.
Uh and on the second question of on the
fired loss ratios you pointed out that
there are XL losses that are baked in
right now. Just wanted to understand
that uh is there you know given the
elevated loss ratio there that you have
reported uh if uh uh if we were to
remove the impact of XL losses also
should we also see some element of uh
that deregulation playing out in the
loss ratio in terms of a uh you know uh
denominator being lower uh for from the
pricing point of view and uh thirdly on
on the crop premium for uh the month of
June I think there was a sizable crop
premium. So that pertains to Maharashtra
and of a similar structure of what it
was done last year. Uh so that would let
me let me let me add to the fire. Let me
take it and I'll ask Gopal to cover the
rest. As Gopal explained the the loss
ratio for those two businesses look a
bit elevated but we are very comfortable
and very happy with the book as as he
explained a big chunk of that
incremental loss issues because of CAT
which happens once in a while. Secondly
the price softening has had a 5 to 6%
impact not not as big as one was
worrying about so in that sense it's a
positive. Uh third is the XL cost is an
upfront cost. As we go through the year,
the entity keeps accreting and the XL
cost gets spread over the whole 12
months. For the Q1, it looks elevated
because it's a smaller book through you
know which is kind of uh absorbing that
increment. So I think overall our uh you
know property and casualty business we
are very happy with the way things are
progressing just to give you an overall
sense of where we see the business and I
ask follow up follow up on that the
price softening part that you mentioned
five to 6%. give. So in in a scenario if
the reinsurance market kind of softens
next year from where it is can can it uh
the softening can be more in our uh this
is this is getting into realms of
speculation uh you know too many factors
are unknown in terms of global
reinsurance markets so there's no point
in talking about it right now maybe we
can discuss this post January one yeah
sure I just add to what said I think one
is I think as keep saying I think which
is what is there in the numbers if you
would have seen on the overall basis uh
while we said our growth in revenues has
been let's say close to about 19% uh x
of crop if you would have seen the
growth in net return premium has been
almost about 23%. Which is a function of
let's say what we retain and what we
kind of uh reinsured but relative to
that if you would have seen the growth
in net has been only about 12%.
uh so that's the catch-up that will
start to happen and this is not just
specific to any particular segment I
think for across segments when we kind
of exhibit growth you will start seeing
NEP doing a catch up over the subsequent
quarters so which is what you should
kind of watch out for and as we always
keep saying for us you should ideally
look at outcomes over years uh if not
ideally on a financial year basis
definitely not quarters I mean quarters
will have lots of elements attached to
it and we Again we will urge everyone to
keep looking at numbers more on annual
basis ideally over years uh because
that's how the insurance cycles
typically work. uh so that's uh just an
addition to what Bam said to your third
point on the crop I think uh pretty much
similar to what we have been talking uh
which is even the one that we have won
in Maharashtra that again operates under
the 80 110 model uh which is where we we
are kind of clear about what kind of uh
risk that we want to undertake and two
as we had discussed even during the
April call potentially there is an
expectation that this year could be an
year of Eleno and hence to that extent
again from an exposure standpoint I
think we would want to be a bit guarded
And even otherwise what we have said uh
even uh earlier as well on crop relative
to our overall numbers I would
definitely want to see it at less than
5% of the aggregate annual revenues. So
that stand kind of pretty much uh
remains the same. uh to your first point
on the overall retail health loss ratios
again I mean this is quarter one numbers
right u I think the range that we gave
is the range that we are comfortable to
kind of operate with uh as a segment and
what we are quite happy and excited
about is the fact that even if you look
at consistently since uh I would say
second half of last year uh and even for
the whole of in fact FI23 we have we
have had outperformance on retail health
visi market I mean if you recolct For
FI23 our growth was almost about 17%.
Industry on retailers grew at 15. Even
quarter one when you look at the numbers
for us individual or retailers grew at
almost about 23%. Market growth was
about 18 19%. So again we have had
outperformance in relative to the
overall market. The good news is even
when you look at it in the context of
standalone health companies our growth
in quarter one has largely been in line
with the standalone health health growth
numbers as well. So hence to that extent
whatever investments that we are doing
on retail health we are quite excited
with the way how the investments have
played out and that's the reason why you
already start to see some small levels
of increase in market share that we have
seen uh which used to be sub 3% right
now we at about close about 3.1% market
share in the retail health individ
as you rightly said there's a lot of
catch up that we have to do and hence to
that extent we will continue to stay
invested in building that distribution
force and uh and loss ratios as I said
will be more an outcome and the range is
what we kind of largely talked about. Q1
honestly again very difficult to comment
on one particular quarter you have to
ideally look at it more on a full year
basis
understood sir uh can I squeeze in a
question uh on group health just I
request you to join by pick sir thank
you
we have a next question from the line of
Praar Sharma from Jeff please go ahead
thank you and congratulations uh to all
of you uh just wanted to get a pulse of
you know this flooding in the northern
Indian parts how big is the business how
should we kind of uh assess any
potential loss that's part one and just
wanted to get a uh sense on you know the
full year uh and next year uh combined
ratio you know uh expectation are we you
know sticking to our RV and guidance so
these were my two questions thank you
so uh the second one is easier to answer
yes we are sticking to it uh in spite of
these losses that cat losses that we had
in this quarter and the the north Indian
floods will come in the Q2 because these
were not uh I mean even now as we speak
uh the losses are coming in uh till now
it doesn't look to be significantly uh
you know an area of concern u but it's
too early to call I think we'll you know
the what happens in floods is that it
takes some time for the customers to
come back and report all the claims. Uh
so I don't want to give a you know false
comfort that it's a no uh value cat
loss. We'll have to wait for some time.
But whatever it is uh you know as a
company
unless these losses are significantly
out of uh sync with the past experiences
I think we'll be we are clear that we
are staying within the same guidance
levels that we talked about.
Thank you. Thank you and best of luck.
Thanks. Thank you. Thank you.
We have our next question from the line
of Niraj Dohal from UBS India. Please go
ahead. Yeah. Hi. Uh so given we have
seen some improvement in June in motor
which is quite impressive. Uh wanted to
understand the outlook going ahead and
are we seeing uh some kind of pricing
improvement which has happened due to
expensive management changes and uh no
hike in uh motor TP pricing for this
year.
uh as we said uh on on the second point
not much we expected some more
improvement because of expensive
management uh you know constraints uh
we've seen some uh you know bit of
correction in terms of certain elements
of you know PA price etc for the sector
so a lot of companies have improved some
element of the pricing but it's not to
the extent that one had you know
expected given the expensive management
as Gopal explained uh you know for a
large number of companies in the sector
it's uh they're over the limit. Uh as of
now we've not seen a change but as he
explained we'll have to see what happens
after quarter one and how the regulator
looks at industry numbers and company
specific numbers. So we'll be watchful.
From our perspective we are well within
the limit. We have a big cushion but
that's doesn't mean that we are going to
be proficient. We are focusing on
building a a sustainable business.
So what kind of growth in motor
portfolio we are kind of now uh given
the momentum is coming back we are
building in
I think as I said earlier I think the
you the uh difficult part is is behind
us is what we think so our expectation
is that we should definitely go in line
with the market for this quarter.
Got it. And uh last question is on the
tenure which you just mentioned the
opening remarks there's the guideline
which from the regulator
uh any incremental color on that.
So n I think uh I think this is
something that we have been talking
about uh earlier as well. So obviously
at an appropriate point of time I think
as we keep saying uh succession planning
is something that actively gets
discussed at the BNRC and at the board
level uh across management levels. So
maybe at an appropriate time I think we
will come back uh if at all uh wherever
we have to make any uh necessary
announcements.
Got it. And on last question on the ICA
bank take by which which which will be
happening over some time had uh any
proceeding or approval from the
regulators happened uh because there's
no update on the exchange for on that
matter. I think they will announce it
whenever they're ready to announce it.
Obviously they'll have to wait for to
get all the approvals but they've got
enough time uh to uh uh to do the same.
Uh as of now there we are awaiting all
clearances from the Got it. Thanks.
Thank you.
Thank you. Thanks. Thank you ladies and
gentlemen. That was the last question
for today. I now hand the conference
over to Mr. Bharodas Gupta for closing
comments. Over to you sir. Thank you.
Thank you everyone for joining. uh and
look forward to uh you know interacting
with you over the next uh few days. Feel
free to reach out to us. Thank you
again. Thank you so much. Thank you on
behalf of ICIC Lombard General Insurance
Company. That concludes this conference.
Thank you for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines.